# Ramin Ala

## Electrical Engineer

- **1** +1 506-262-9550
- ✓ ramin.ala@gmail.com
- in Linkedin
- Website
- 780 Montgomery St., Fredericton, NB, Canada



#### **SUMMARY**

I am an electrical engineer with eight years of industrial experience between 2010 and 2019. After that, I joined the University of New Brunswick as a Ph.D. student and research assistant as well as working as a teaching assistant. During my doctoral studies, I gained valuable experiences in data science. I completed two relevant courses with outstanding grades (earning A+ in both), and a section in my thesis focused on the application of data science. I am currently in the final stages of defending my Ph.D. and actively seeking employment opportunities.

Please feel free to visit my website, where I am gradually adding more information. You can find it here.

#### **EDUCATION**

• Ph.D. 2019 – 2023

University of New Brunswick

New Brunswick, Canada

**Thesis:** Efficient and Ultra Low Mass Harmonic Radar

Transponders for Insect Tracking Applications

• M.Sc. 2007 – 2010

K. N. Toosi University of Technology Tehran, Iran

• B.Sc. 2002 – 2007

University of Isfahan Isfahan, Iran

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### • Iranian Space Research Center

2016 - 2018

Tehran, Iran

Senior RF Designer

#### • Ertebatat Baregheh Pardis

2014 - 2016

Tehran, Iran

Senior RF Designer

• OTS 2010 – 2014

Tehran, Iran

RF and Microwave Engineer

#### **SKILLS**

#### • Design expertise:

- Designing Electronic circuits
- Designing Microwave active and passive devices
- Testing and troubleshooting the wide range of devices, up to the frequency of 26.5 Hz

#### • Lab expertise:

- All electronic lab instruments
- All Microwave and RF lab instruments (Vector Network Analyzer, Spectrum Analyzer, . . .)
- Antenna measurements in Anechoic Chamber

#### • Data Science:

Proficient in data manipulation and analysis using R and Python packages, ensuring efficient workflows. I have some experience in

#### SOFTWARE PROFICIENCY

#### • Some of the industrial tools:

Computer Simulation Technology (CST)Altium Designer

PathWave Advanced Design System (ADS)Ansys HFSS

#### • Programming and other Tools:

R (Programming language)MATLAB

- LaTaX

### **JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS**

- 1. R. Ala, C. D. Rouse and B. G. Colpitts, "An Extra Low-Mass Harmonic Radar Transponder for Insect Tracking Applications," in *IEEE Transactions on Radar Systems*, vol. 1, pp. 146-154, 2023, doi: 10.1109/TRS.2023.3286270.
- 2. R. Ala, B. Ahmadi, "A comparative study of high-power low-pass filters for satellite communications," *Microw Opt Technol Lett*, 2019; 61: 1968-1971. doi: 10.1002/mop.31783.

#### **REFERENCES**

1. Dr Chris Rouse	Professor at UNB	chris.rouse@unb.ca
2. Dr Bruce Colpitts	Professor at UNB	colpitts@unb.ca
3. Dr Berent Petersen	Professor at UNB	Brent.Petersen@unb.ca